A Guide to the American Civil Liberties Union--Southern Women's Rights Project 1976-1981
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
American Civil Liberties Union--Southern Women's Rights Project 1976-1981
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 178
American Civil Liberties Union--Southern Women's Rights Project
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open with restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Southern Women's Rights Project (SWRP) located in Richmond is affiliated with the American Civil Liberties Union. The project deals with issues of special concern for women. Topics include: abortion, employment discrimination, ERA, education discrimination, prisoner's rights, children's rights, sexual harassment, and spouse abuse.
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence with various chapters of the ACLU in Southern states, State legislation, periodicals, pamphlets, and newspaper clippings.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Files are arranged by subject and chronologically therein.
Organization
Series I--Correspondence n.d., 1976-1981
Series II--State Legislation 1976-1977
Series III--General Files n.d., 1976-1981
Series IV--Periodicals
Series V-Restricted
Series VI-(one box of miscellaneous materials)
Contents List
- Correspondence n.d 1976-181
  - Alabama Contacts n.d. (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Alabama Correspondence 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1.2)
  - Arkansas Contacts 1977 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Arkansas Correspondence 1977-1980 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - Battered Women 1978 (Box-folder 1.5)
  - Beyea, Peratic, etc. 1977-1979 (Box-folder 1.6)
  - Correspondence (see also Out-Corr.; Recent-Corr.) 1978 (Box-folder 1.7)
  - Complaints, Requests 1978 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Contact Persons 1977-1980 (Box-folder 1.9)
  - ERA 1979 (Box-folder 1.10)
  - Employment-Military Correspondence 1977 (Box-folder 1.11)
  - Florida Correspondence 1977 (Box-folder 1.12)
  - General 1980 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Georgia Contacts 1977 (Box-folder 1.14)
  - Georgia Correspondence 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1.15)
  - J.P. Stevens 1977-1978 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - Kentucky Contacts 1977 (Box-folder 2.2)
  - Kentucky Correspondence 1977 (Box-folder 2.3)
  - Legal Requests 1979 (Box-folder 2.4)
  - Legal Requests 1979 (Box-folder 2.5)
  - Legal Requests: Southern Project 1977 (Box-folder 2.6)
  - Literature Orders 1979 (Box-folder 2.7)
  - Literature Orders to be Filled 1980 (Box-folder 2.8)
  - Louisiana Correspondence 1977-1979 (Box-folder 2.9)
  - Membership 1978 (Box-folder 2.10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1979 (Box-folder 2.11)
  - Mississippi Contacts 1977 (Box-folder 2.12)
  - Mississippi Correspondence 1977-1978 (Box-folder 2.13)
  - National Correspondence 1977-1979 (Box-folder 3.1)
  - Non-South Affiliates 1977-1979 (Box-folder 3.1)
  - North Carolina Contacts 1978 (Box-folder 3.2)
  - North Carolina Correspondence 1977-1979 (Box-folder 3.3)
  - Out Correspondence 1979 (Box-folder 3.4)
  - Recent Correspondence (Liz) 1978 (Box-folder 3.5)
  - South Carolina Contacts 1977-1978 (Box-folder 3.6)
  - South Carolina Correspondence 1977-1978 (Box-folder 3.7)
  - Southern Project-Affiliates 1978 (Box-folder 3.8)
  - Southern Project-Literature Speaker Requests 1977-1979 (Box-folder 3.9)
  - Sponsors 1980 (Box-folder 3.10)
  - SWRP 1978 (Box-folder 3.11)
  - SWRP Org. Contacts-CLUW-Pubs. 1977 (Box-folder 3.12)
  - SWRP Org. Contacts-SEJ 1977-1978 (Box-folder 3.13)
  - SWRP Org. Contacts-So. Exposure 1976-1978 (Box-folder 3.14)
  - SWRP Org. Contacts-Other ACLU Projects 1978 (Box-folder 3.15)
  - Tennessee Contacts 1977-1978 (Box-folder 3.16)
  - Tennessee Correspondence 1977 (Box-folder 3.17)
  - Virginia Contacts 1977 (Box-folder 3.18)
  - Virginia Correspondence 1977-1978 (Box-folder 3.19)
  - Vocational Ed. Correspondence 1977-1978 (Box-folder 3.20)
- State Legislation 1976-1977
  - Alabama 1976-1977 (Box-folder 4.1)
  - Arkansas 1977 (Box-folder 4.2)
  - Florida 1977 (Box-folder 4.3)
  - Georgia 1977 (Box-folder 4.4)
  - Kentucky 1977 (Box-folder 4.5)
  - Louisiana 1977 (Box-folder 4.6)
  - North Carolina 1977 (Box-folder 4.7)
  - South Carolina 1977 (Box-folder 4.8)
- General Files 1976-1981
  - Abortion-Alabama 1978 (Box-folder 5.1)
  - Abortion-General Information 1977-1978 (Box-folder 5.2)
  - Abortion-Health 1978-1979 (Box-folder 5.3)
  - Abortion-National Legislative Lobbying 1978 (Box-folder 5.4)
  - Abortion-North Carolina 1977-1979 (Box-folder 5.5)
  - Abortion-Tennessee n.d. (Box-folder 5.6)
  - Abortion-Virginia 1977-1978 (Box-folder 5.7)
  - ACLU Issues-Bakke 1977-1978 (Box-folder 5.8)
  - ACLU Legal Department 1977-1978 (Box-folder 5.9)
  - ACLU Office Manual for Volunteers 1978 (Box-folder 5.10)
  - ACLU Policy/Positions 1978 (Box-folder 5.11)
  - ACLU Staff/Board of Directors 1978 (Box-folder 5.12)
  - ACLU/WRP Mailing List (Box-folder 6.0)
  - ACLU/WRP Docket 1977-1980 (Box-folder 6.1)
  - ACLU/WRP Notes 1977-1978 (Box-folder 6.2)
  - ACLU/WRP Staff Minutes and Memos 1977-1979 (Box-folder 6.3)
  - Affiliate Memos 1978-1979 (Box-folder 6.4)
  - American Arbitration Association n.d. (Box-folder 6.5)
  - American Rodeo Association 1978 (Box-folder 6.6)
  - American Woman's Museum n.d. (Box-folder 6.7)
  - Anniversary Orders 1980 (Box-folder 6.8)
  - Anniversary-60th 1979-1980 (Box-folder 6.9)
  - Antioch Trip-Betsy Brinson 1980 (Box-folder 6.10)
  - Apprenticeship n.d. (Box-folder 6.11)
  - Arkansas Conference 1978 (Box-folder 6.12)
  - Arkansas Foodworkers Project 1980 (Box-folder 6.13)
  - Battered Women 1977 (Box-folder 7.1)
  - Battered Women Action Guide 1977-1978 (Box-folder 7.2)
  - Battered Women Handbooks 1977 (Box-folder 7.3)
  - Battered Women/Domestic Violence Act 1978 (Box-folder 7.4)
  - Battered Women Legislation 1977-1978 (Box-folder 7.5)
  - Battered Women Litigation 1977 (Box-folder 7.6)
  - Battered Women Miscellaneous 1978 (Box-folder 7.7)
  - Battered Women Proposal 1974-1978 (Box-folder 7.8)
  - Battered Women Resource List n.d. (Box-folder 7.9)
  - Battered Women "Response" 1976-1977 (Box-folder 7.10)
  - Battered Women Speeches Articles 1976-1977 (Box-folder 7.11)
  - Bicentennial Papers 1979 (Box-folder 7.12)
  - Black Women and the Law Con. 1980-1981 (Box-folder 7.13)
  - Campaign Reports National Memos 1977-1978 (Box-folder 8.1)
  - Colorado Proposal 1980 (Box-folder 8.2)
  - CETA 1978-1980 (Box-folder 8.3)
  - Changes 1981 (Box-folder 8.4)
  - Commitments Upcoming 1980 (Box-folder 8.5)
  - Committee on Women in Prison 1979 (Box-folder 8.6)
  - Communiques 1977-1978 (Box-folder 8.7)
  - Complaints-Cases 1977-1978 (Box-folder 8.8)
  - Conference Commitments 1980 (Box-folder 9.1)
  - Conference Expenses 1980-1981 (Box-folder 9.2)
  - Conference Follow ups 1980 (Box-folder 9.3)
  - Conference Org. Memo 1978 (Box-folder 9.4)
  - Conference Participants 1980 (Box-folder 9.5)
  - Conference Press 1980 (Box-folder 9.6)
  - Conference Talk n.d. (Box-folder 9.7)
  - Constitutional Amendment 1980 (Box-folder 9.8)
  - Contract Compliance 1980 (Box-folder 9.9)
  - Con. Con. Project 1979 (Box-folder 9.10)
  - Constitutional Convention 1977-1978 (Box-folder 9.11)
  - Detente-CIA Current ACLU Memos 1980 (Box-folder 9.12)
  - Displaced Homemakers 1978 (Box-folder 9.13)
  - Duren 1979 (Box-folder 9.14)
  - Education Affirmative Action Reports 1977 (Box-folder 9.15)
  - Education Athletics ACLU Policy 1977 (Box-folder 9.16)
  - Education Athletics Model Complaints 1978 (Box-folder 9.17)
  - Education Text Book Bias 1977-1979 (Box-folder 10.1)
  - EEOC Complaints 1979 (Box-folder 10.2)
  - EEOC Regulation 1980 (Box-folder 10.3)
  - Employment 1977 (Box-folder 10.4)
  - Employment-Affirmative Action Articles 1977 (Box-folder 10.5)
  - Employment Conference Richmond, Virginia 1980 (Box-folder 10.6)
  - Employment Council Funding Requests 1978-1979 (Box-folder 10.7)
  - Employment EEOC Reorganization 1977 (Box-folder 10.8)
  - Employment-Materials for Handbook 1980 (Box-folder 10.9)
  - Employment-Military-Owens vs Rumsfeld 1977 (Box-folder 10.10)
  - Employment Monitors Local Government 1977 (Box-folder 10.11)
  - Reproductive Health-Articles 1978 (Box-folder 10.12)
  - Resources 1980 (Box-folder 10.13)
  - Employment-Retail Clerks-Winn Dixie 1974-1979 (Box-folder 10.14)
  - Employment Seniority 1977 (Box-folder 10.15)
  - Employment and Women in the South 1980 (Box-folder 10.16)
  - ERA 1977 (Box-folder 10.17)
  - ERA Adopt an Affiliate Project 1979-1980 (Box-folder 10.18)
  - ERA America 1979 (Box-folder 10.19)
  - ERA America Working Papers 1978-1979 (Box-folder 10.20)
  - ERA Arrests Publicity 1978 (Box-folder 11.1)
  - ERA Article 1979 (Box-folder 11.2)
  - ERA Articles 1971-1980 (Box-folder 11.3)
  - ERA Education for Minority Women 1979 (Box-folder 11.4)
  - ERA Educational Materials 1977 (Box-folder 11.5)
  - ERA Extension 1978 (Box-folder 11.6)
  - ERA Florida Telephone Campaign 1979 (Box-folder 11.7)
  - ERA Future 1978 (Box-folder 11.8)
  - ERA Louisiana Project 1979 (Box-folder 11.9)
  - ERA Literature 1973-1979 (Box-folder 11.10)
  - ERA Literature 1973-1979 (Box-folder 11.11)
  - ERA, Memorandum 1979 (Box-folder 12.1)
  - ERA Misc. 1977 (Box-folder 12.2)
  - ERA Misc. Clippings 1972-1979 (Box-folder 12.3)
  - ERA-Other Southern States 1977-1979 (Box-folder 12.4)
  - ERA Referendum n.d. (Box-folder 12.5)
  - ERA Rescission 1978-1979 (Box-folder 12.6)
  - ERA-Speeches 1978 (Box-folder 12.7)
  - ERA-Telephone Fundraising Campaign 1977 (Box-folder 12.8)
  - ERA-Virginia Ratification Council 1977-1979 (Box-folder 12.9)
  - Women's Rights 1975-1978 (Box-folder 13.1)
  - ERA Working Women Pamphlet 1978 (Box-folder 13.2)
  - FDA Promotion 1980 (Box-folder 13.3)
  - Federal Judgeships 1979 (Box-folder 13.4)
  - Female Offender Conference 1974-1977 (Box-folder 13.5)
  - Female Offenders Grant 1977 (Box-folder 13.6)
  - Future Conferences 1978 (Box-folder 13.7)
  - Gardner, George 1978 (Box-folder 13.8)
  - Georgia 1977-1979 (Box-folder 13.9)
  - Georgia Affirmative Action Proposal 1977-1980 (Box-folder 13.10)
  - Georgia Vocational Ed. Project 1979-1980 (Box-folder 14.1)
  - Georgia Women's Prison Construction 1979 (Box-folder 14.2)
  - Georgia Church State Proposal 1980 (Box-folder 14.3)
  - Ginsburg UNC 1978 (Box-folder 14.4)
  - Goochland Suit 1974-1978 (Box-folder 14.5)
  - GR$R Affiliates 1980 (Box-folder 14.6)
  - Handbook ACLU 1979 (Box-folder 14.7)
  - Handbook on Legal Rights of Minority Women 1980 (Box-folder 14.8)
  - Health Insurance 1978 (Box-folder 14.9)
  - Henrico County-James, Margaret 1980 (Box-folder 14.10)
  - Henrico County Sheriff's Department 1979 (Box-folder 14.11)
  - Housing, Education, and Welfare; dept. of. (HEW) 1978 (Box-folder 15.1)
  - Highlander 1979 (Box-folder 15.2)
  - Housing 1980 (Box-folder 15.3)
  - IWY 1977 (Box-folder 15.4)
  - Johnson, Sonia 1979 (Box-folder 15.5)
  - J.P. Stevens 1978-1980 (Box-folder 15.6)
  - J.P. Stevens Articles 1978-1980 (Box-folder 15.7)
  - J.P. Stevens Affiliates 1977-1978 (Box-folder 15.8)
  - J.P. Stevens Brochure 1978 (Box-folder 15.9)
  - J.P. Stevens Bd. 1978-1979 (Box-folder 15.10)
  - J.P. Stevens Stockholders Meeting 1979 (Box-folder 15.11)
  - J.P. Stevens Project 1978 (Box-folder 15.12)
  - Kentucky Employment Conference 1979 (Box-folder 16.1)
  - Kilgo, Edna 1978-1980 (Box-folder 16.2)
  - Klu Klux Klan 1978 (Box-folder 16.3)
  - Labor Law 1980 (Box-folder 16.4)
  - Labor Law Reform 1977 (Box-folder 16.5)
  - Local Arrangements 1980 (Box-folder 16.6)
  - LEAA Rev. Sharing Remedies 1979 (Box-folder 16.7)
  - Legal Developments-Current Law 1977-1979 (Box-folder 16.8)
  - Literature Orders 1979-1980 (Box-folder 16.9)
  - Litigation Homemakers Exemption 1977 (Box-folder 16.10)
  - Louisiana Conference 1979 (Box-folder 16.11)
  - Louisiana Litigation 1978 (Box-folder 16.12)
  - Marriage and Divorce n.d. (Box-folder 17.1)
  - Mc Roe vs. Harris 1980 (Box-folder 17.2)
  - Media Campaign 1978 (Box-folder 17.3)
  - Medicaid Funding in Va 1978-1979 (Box-folder 17.4)
  - Medical Litigation in Va 1978 (Box-folder 17.5)
  - Minority Workers Bureau of Labor Reports 1980 (Box-folder 17.6)
  - Miscellaneous 1977-1978 (Box-folder 17.7)
  - Misc. Pamphlets 1975-1980 (Box-folder 17.8)
  - Misc. Women's Issues Govn. Spying 1977 (Box-folder 17.9)
  - Misc. Women's Issues Rural Issues n.d. (Box-folder 17.10)
  - Mississippi Employment Conference 1979 (Box-folder 17.12)
  - National Convocation on Women n.d. (Box-folder 17.13)
  - Nazis-Skokie 1978 (Box-folder 18.1)
  - Nazis Right Wing 1978 (Box-folder 18.2)
  - NCCLU Employment Conference 1978-1979 (Box-folder 18.3)
  - Network Pregnancy 1978 (Box-folder 18.4)
  - New Directory Conference 1979 (Box-folder 18.5)
  - Newsletter 1980 (Box-folder 18.6)
  - Newsletter 1980 (Box-folder 18.7)
  - Norfolk Employment Conference 1978-1979 (Box-folder 18.8)
  - Non-Traditional Jobs Projects 1978 (Box-folder 18.9)
  - North Carolina Conference 1978 (Box-folder 18.10)
  - Northern VA Women's Medical Center Litigation 1978 (Box-folder 18.12)
  - Pay Equity Conference Planning Notes 1980 (Box-folder 18.13)
  - Pay Equity Task Force 1980 (Box-folder 18.14)
  - Photographs 1980 (Box-folder 18.15)
  - Pro-choice Legal Developments 1979 (Box-folder 18.16)
  - Pro-choice Speeches Mixed Articles 1979 (Box-folder 18.17)
  - Pro-choice Regional Conferences 1977-1978 (Box-folder 18.18)
  - Proposals 1977-1978 (Box-folder 19.1)
  - Promotion 1980 (Box-folder 19.2)
  - Quarterly Reports 1980 (Box-folder 19.3)
  - Radiation 1979 (Box-folder 19.4)
  - Regional Communiques 1977-1979 (Box-folder 19.5)
  - Report-Ideas for Articles 1979-1980 (Box-folder 19.6)
  - Report Samples (New Mailing List) 1980 (Box-folder 19.7)
  - Reproductive Health Articles 1978 (Box-folder 19.8)
  - Reproductive Freedom Project 1978 (Box-folder 20.1)
  - Right to Life 1978 (Box-folder 20.2)
  - Roanoke 1978 (Box-folder 20.3)
  - Ronald Reagan 1980 (Box-folder 20.4)
  - *S-1437* (Senate Bill) 1977 (Box-folder 20.5)
  - Savannah Conference 1978-1979 (Box-folder 20.6)
  - SCEE 1979-1981 (Box-folder 20.7)
  - Seaboard Railroad 1979-1980 (Box-folder 20.8)
  - Sept. Meeting 1979 (Box-folder 20.9)
  - Sears Litigation 1979 (Box-folder 20.10)
  - Sexual Harassment Cassidy 1980 (Box-folder 20.11)
  - Silkwood, Karen 1975-1978 (Box-folder 20.12)
  - Simon Study-Women and Crime 1978 (Box-folder 21.1)
  - South Carolina 1978-1979 (Box-folder 21.2)
  - South Carolina Employment 1979 (Box-folder 21.3)
  - Southern Board Delegates meetings 1979 (Box-folder 21.4)
  - Southern Coalition for Educational Equity 1980 (Box-folder 21.5)
  - Southern Project Affiliate Newsletter 1977-1978 (Box-folder 21.6)
  - Southern Project Grant Proposals 1976-1977 (Box-folder 21.7)
  - Southern Project News Releases 1979 (Box-folder 21.8)
  - Southern Project-So. Dir. Con. 1977 (Box-folder 21.9)
  - Southern Regional Conference 1979 (Box-folder 22.1)
  - Southern States Misc. 1977-1978 (Box-folder 22.2)
  - Speaker Biographies 1980 (Box-folder 22.3)
  - Steering Committee 1980 (Box-folder 22.4)
  - Staff Council 1978 (Box-folder 22.5)
  - State Legislation 1975-1979 (Box-folder 22.6)
  - Sterilization 1978-1980 (Box-folder 22.7)
  - Sterilization Doe vs. Pierce n.d. (Box-folder 22.8)
  - Sterilization Funding Va 1980 (Box-folder 22.9)
  - Sterilization Health 1978 (Box-folder 22.10)
  - Student Interns 1978 (Box-folder 22.11)
  - Supreme Court Decisions 1977 (Box-folder 22.12)
  - Southern Women's Rights Project (SWRP) Advisory Committee 1979 (Box-folder 22.13)
  - SWRP Early Organ. Memos 1977 (Box-folder 22.14)
  - Tennessee Employment Conference 1979 (Box-folder 22.15)
  - Title IX Regulations 1979 (Box-folder 22.16)
  - Unratified State Update 1979 (Box-folder 23.1)
  - VA Advisory Committee 1978 (Box-folder 23.2)
  - VA Vocational Ed. Plan 1977-1980 (Box-folder 23.3)
  - VA vs Fowler and Clark Defense 1978 (Box-folder 23.4)
  - VA vs. Fowler and Clark Prosecution 1978 (Box-folder 23.5)
  - Vocational Ed. 1975 (Box-folder 23.6)
  - Vocational Ed. 1977-1978 (Box-folder 23.7)
  - Vocational Ed. 1971-1978 (Box-folder 24.1)
  - Vocational Ed. 1971-1978 (Box-folder 24.2)
  - Vocational Ed. 1971-1978 (Box-folder 24.3)
  - Vocational Ed. Apprenticeship Training 1975-1978 (Box-folder 24.4)
  - Vocational Ed. Complaints 1977 (Box-folder 24.5)
  - Vocational Ed. Conference Georgia 1977-1978 (Box-folder 24.6)
  - Vocational Ed. Laws and Regulations 1977-1978 (Box-folder 24.7)
  - Vocational Ed. Misc. 1977-1979 (Box-folder 25.1)
  - Vocational Ed. Misc. 1977-1979 (Box-folder 25.2)
  - Washington Extension Challenge n.d. (Box-folder 25.3)
  - White House Conference on the Family 1978-1980 (Box-folder 25.4)
  - Women and Health 1977-1978 (Box-folder 25.5)
  - Women and Radiation Conference Materials 1980 (Box-folder 25.6)
  - Women in Ministry 1979-1980 (Box-folder 25.7)
  - Women in Prison and Children Reports 1980 (Box-folder 25.8)
  - Women in Prison-Disadvantaged 1977-1978 (Box-folder 26.1)
  - Women In Prison-Female Offender 1978-1980 (Box-folder 26.2)
  - Women in Prison-Job Training 1978 (Box-folder 26.3)
  - Women in Prison Newsletter 1980 (Box-folder 26.4)
  - Women in Prison Richmond Times Dispatch 1980 (Box-folder 26.5)
  - Women in Prison-Survey of Bettered Women 1978 (Box-folder 26.6)
  - Women on Death Row 1978-1979 (Box-folder 26.7)
  - Women's Rights n.d. (Box-folder 26.8)
  - Work Discrimination n.d. (Box-folder 26.9)
- Periodicals
  - Abortion The Double Standard Dr Jane Furlong-Cahill Ph.d. (Box 27)
  - Abortion Surveillance U.S. Dept. of Health, Education, and Welfare 1975 (Box 27)
  - ACLU Lawyer #3 (Box 27)
  - Agenda vol. 7 no. 5 (Box 27)
  - Alabama Law Review vol. 29 no.2 (Box 27)
  - ACLU Annual Report 1977 (Box 27)
  - American Criminal Law Review vol. 14 no. 3 (Box 27)
  - American Women Today and Tomorrow Barbara Everitt Bryant (Box 27)
  - Annual Report-Alexandria Commission on the Status of Women 1976 (Box 27)
  - Annual Report to the Governor of Virginia 1976 (Box 27)
  - Annual Statistical Report of Felons and Misdemeanants Committed to the State Penal System During the Year Ending June 30, 1974 And Felons Confined in the penal System June 30, 1974 (Box 27)
  - Application for Grants Under Womens Educational Equity Act Program 1978 (Box 27)
  - Athletic Scholarships for Women in Michigan Colleges and Universities 1981 (Box 27)
  - Battered Women Manfred Ohrenstein (Box 27)
  - Battered Women: Part II County Profiles Manfred Ohrenstein (Box 27)
  - CETA A Citizens Action Guide April 1979 (Box 27)
  - Children's Rights Report vol. 2 no. 1,2,7,8,9,10 vol. 3 no. 2,3 (Box 27)
  - Civil Liberties 318,320,322,323 (Box 27)
  - The Civil Liberties Review vol. 3 no. 1,5 vol. 4 no. 1,3,4 (Box 27)
  - Civil Rights Digest vol. 6 no. 3 (Box 27)
  - Comparison of Proposals for Reforming the Intelligence Agencies 1978 (Box 27)
  - Constitutional Aspects of the Right to Limit Childbearing 1975 (Box 27)
  - Cooperative Approaches to Civil Rights a Statewide Conference 1980 (Box 27)
  - Crisis: Three Mile Island Washington Post (Box 27)
  - CRA Citizen's Action Guide (Box 27)
  - Comprehensive Employment and Training Act and its Services Women 1976 (Box 27)
  - Daily Breakthrough Nov. 20, 1977 (Box 27)
  - Death Watch# 4,5,6 (Box 27)
  - Decade for Women World Plan Action (Box 27)
  - Directory of Community Services United Way of Greater Richmond 1976 (Box 27)
  - The Dissemination Center for WEEAP (Box 27)
  - Employment Needs of Women Offenders: a Program Design pamphlet 13 (Box 27)
  - Enlightenment Enrichment in Education 1975 (Box 27)
  - Equality on the Job AAC (Box 27)
  - The ERA Supporter's Handbook 1974 (Box 27)
  - Exemplary Strategies for Elimination of Sex Bias in Vocational Education Programs Shelia Maher (Box 27)
  - Exemplary Vocational Guidance Projects Virginia Vocational Guidance Programs (Box 27)
  - Expanding Adolescent Role Expectations Community Service Education Dept. (Box 27)
  - An Exploratory Study of Women in the Health Professions Schools vol. 9 Public Health (Box 27)
  - Federal Fair Housing Enforcement Effort U.S. Comm. on Civil Rights Federal Register Parts V, VI, IX (Box 27)
  - Federal State, Local Government 1975 (Box 27)
  - Female Offender 1979 (Box 27)
  - Female Offenders: Who Are They and What are the Problems Confronting Them? U.S. General Accounting Office (Box 27)
  - Female Offender Workshop Guide 1977 (Box 27)
  - First Principals vol. 3 no. 2,3 vol. 4 no. 1,3,9,10 (Box 27)
  - FRAC's Guide to the Food Stamps Program 4th Edition (Box 27)
  - Georgia State Plan for the Administration of Vocational Education Part II (Box 28)
  - Government in the Sunshine Emphasis: Georgia Ronald L. Plesser (Box 28)
  - Governor's Commission on the Status of Women 1975-1976 (Box 28)
  - Guia a los Derechos de la Mujer Que Trbaja 1975 (Box 28)
  - A Guide to Federal Laws and Regulations Prohibiting Sex Discrimination (Box 28)
  - A Guide to Seeking Funds from CETA U.S. Dept. of Labor 1977 and 1979 (Box 28)
  - Handbook for Battered, Abused Women Darlene Duncan (Box 28)
  - Handbook for Commissions on the Status of Women, Kathyrn F. Clarenbach (Box 28)
  - 1975 Handbook on Women Workers Bulletin 297 1975 (Box 28)
  - Housing & Museums & Dancing VCU Info Clinics Legal Aid Day care Leases & A Richmond Self-Help Manual VCU (Box 28)
  - Key Factors Affecting Change in the South ACTS (Box 28)
  - Kentucky's Observance of International Women's Year 1977 (Box 28)
  - The Judge's Journal vol. 16 no. 3 (Box 28)
  - In the Matter of Edna Smith, Brief for the Appellant (Box 28)
  - The Impact of the Hyde Amendment on Medically Necessary Abortions ACLU (Box 28)
  - How to Tame the CETA Beast Older Women's League Educational Fund (Box 28)
  - How to Erase Sex Discrimination in Vocational Education ACLU-WRP (Box 28)
  - The Legal Status of Homemakers in: Alabama (Box 28)
  - The Legal status of Homemakers in: Arkansas (Box 28)
  - The Legal Status of Homemakers in: Florida (Box 28)
  - The Legal Status of Homemakers in: Georgia (Box 28)
  - The Legal Status of Homemakers in: Kentucky (Box 28)
  - The Legal Status of Homemakers in: Louisiana (Box 28)
  - The Legal Status of Homemakers in: Mississippi (Box 28)
  - The Legal Status of Homemakers in: North Carolina (Box 28)
  - The Legal Status of Homemakers in: South Carolina (Box 28)
  - The Legal Status of Homemakers in: Tennessee (Box 28)
  - Litigation Under the Federal Freedom of Information Act and Privacy Act 1981 (Box 28)
  - Making it Work! A Booklet of Activities to Encourage the Development of Co-ed Physical Education Programs Office for Sex Equity (Box 28)
  - Majority Report vol. 7 no. 8 (Box 28)
  - National Plan of Action National Women's Conference (Box 28)
  - National Right to Life News (Box 28)
    vol. 4 no. 11, 12 vol. 5 no.1, 2a, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9
  - National Womens' Conference-American Women on the Move 1977 (Box 28)
  - New Pioneers North Carolina Dept. of Public Instruction (Box 28)
  - No More Cages vol.1 no. 2 (Box 28)
  - No Room at the Top ACLU Vocational Education Monitoring Project (Box 28)
  - Occupational Employment Statistics Virginia Employment Commission (Box 28)
  - Organization Manual of the ACLU 1976 (Box 28)
  - Organizing Notes (Box 28)
    vol.2 no. 2, 3, 4, 7
  - Peer Perspective Newsletter (Box 28)
    vol. 1 no.1, 2, 3, 4, 5, vol. 2 no. 1, 2, 3 vol. 3 no. 1, 2, 3 vol. 4 no. 1, 2, vol. 5 no. 1
  - Policy Guide of the ACLU 1976 (Box 28)
  - Prejudice and Discrimination Social Science Staff of the Educational Research Council of America (Box 28)
  - Prison Law Monitor vol. 2 no. 4 (Box 28)
  - Prisons in North Carolina N.C. Advisory Committee to the U.S. Comm. on Civil Rights (Box 28)
  - Prisoners Assistance Directory National Prison Project (Box 28)
  - Privacy Report (Box 28)
    vol. 5 no. 1, 2, 4, 5, 6, 8, 9